...degrees in downtown
Los Angeles right now.
I've been waiting for 15 minutes.
- What? I thought you were in stuck.
Thought you were running late. Papers?
- Yeah.
Pissed off? I'm just doing my portion.
- No, no. I know, I know.
You're my guy, Jerry.
Margolese Holdings, morning. How may
I direct your call? Yes, he is.
I'll put you through.
- Hey, Estelle.
Is that Nayman's little nephew?
- Yeah, that's Big Tom.
Big Tom. How's it goin', Big Tom?
- Hey, hey. Look.
Shh. See? See?
- What are you scaring the kid for?
Did you get that fucking passport?
- Yes.
I have issues.
- Issues, Jerry, means,
to write you a check every week.
- I can explain what happened.
You say "I can explain" when it's
a once in a blue moon thing.
It's every time with you, Jerry.
- I can understand that perspective.
Uh, but I've been having some personal
problems, uh, with my life.
My girlfriend, she's a great girl,
but she has complaints. I don't have,
but she has complaints.
I can't even believe this,
but we go to a group.
Last week, when you guys told me
to pick up the thing at the thing,
well, Samantha says she needs
the car to pick up some things.
And, I don't have to tell you boys,
I mean, things got heated, right?
She hid them.
Oh, the keys. She hid them.
You know,
and I couldn't get to the thing on
time, and it all got messed up,
and I think that maybe, maybe some
things aren't meant to happen.
Jerry, you're a fucking moron.
Here are your options. Number one:
I roll you up to the neck in a carpet,
stuff you in the back of a Sedan
and light you on fire with gasoline.
Choice one.
- Yeah.
No. 2: You like sex and travel?
Do you like to have sex?
Do you like to travel?
You get on a flight to Mexico.
All 10-dollar hookers you can shake
your stick at. Pick up a pistol that
belongs Margolese. What's it gonna be?
- Ok. I was under the impression with
Margolese getting out of jail and all,
that the last job was my last job.
You fucked up that job.
- You fucked up.
Yeah. This job will be your last job.
- Ok, but a trip right now...
He asked for you. You want me to call
him and let him know you can't go?
Because I'll call. I'd love to.
You're goin' on a fucking trip.
The town's called San Miguel. You look
for a kid in a bar, the EI Alamo.
This is a simple fucking task.
You write it down.
Shit! Roll up your sleeves!
- Ow!
His name is Beck. He's waiting on you,
and got this particular gun,
When you find him, bring him and the
gun back Stateside to me, got it?
Last chance. Even he's getting tired
of your shit. He told me so.
I'll take care of it, Bernie.
Vaya con Dios, motherfucker.
You're in coach.
Baby, what are you doing?
- You said this was your last job!
What do you want me to say? "I'm sorry
I can't facilitate that request.
The lady wants me to quit." Huh?
- Yes! Something like that!
I'm not in insurance, sweetie!
- You get on that plane, you will
never, never, ever see me again.
You got me? We talked about this.
I wanted us to go to Las Vegas
for me. Not you, no. Me.
Baby, you're overreacting. Ok?
- Don't do that! Don't you do that!
Don't diminish my needs!
- Sweet, I have no choice. I gotta go.
I go down there. I come right back.
- "I, I, I, I, I!"
What would the group say about that.
- No! You cannot use that against me!
We're not even technically married,
but I go, don't I? The whole group
thinks we're married. I accepted the
potato slicer graciously for
our anniversary. Right? I go along.
- That's it. That is it.
You go along! You don't want to get
married to me, and this is the way
that you're dealing with it!
Huh? You're back to
the same old selfish, self-involved,
vile, disgusting self! God. You are...
You're missing the grand design here!
If I don't go, I'm dead.
Yeah. It's a little difficult to carry
on a relationship if I'm stuffed with
straw and formaldehyde. Now, if
anyone, anyone is being selfish...
Oh! Now you blame-shift?
You are blame-shifting?
Stop the analyzing!
- I'm calling a time-out!
All right. Jerry,
I want you to acknowledge
that my needs mean nothing to you and
you are a selfish prick and a liar.
Oh, my God!
- Jerry, acknowledge.
Ok. I will acknowledge
that I promised
I would go to Vegas with you.
But now we're just slightly delayed.
If you want to construe my wanting
to stay alive as being selfish,
well, then, ok. But I have every
intention of going with you,
because your needs are very
important to me, sweetheart.
Come on. Look at all my stuff here,
all over the pavement.
Come on, baby. Huh?
What do you say? Ok?
I'm going with or without you, Jerry.
What's it gonna be?
A bastard!
- A bastard. What happened to, uh,
"sweetheart" and "big love" and all
those things you called me in
the bedroom last night?
- The only thing that I'm interested in
calling you, Jerry, is a cab!
Excuse me, speak English?
English? Excuse me.
You speak English?
- What?
All set, Mr. Welbach. If you go to
the front there, a shuttle will pick
you up and take you to your car.
- Hey, what kind of car is it exactly?
It's a Chrysler. Brand-new, sir.
Is there a problem, Mr. Welbach?
You know, it's my first trip
to Mexico, and, well, a Chrysler?
I drive a Chrysler in America.
I was thinking maybe you might have
something a little more authentic...
- Mexican?
Yeah. You know. Get into the spirit.
- Your first time? Yeah.
Wow. Exciting.
Yeah, Speedy Gonzales.
- Let's see what we can do for you.
Oh, I think I have just the thing.
How would you like
an EI Camino?
- Oh. I like that. That's good. Yeah.
EI Camino...
In my EI Camino...
Fucker.
You are in the wrong place, America.
- Yeah, I'm aware of that.
What you want here?
Uh, tequila.
I asked because no one like you
comes to this place.
It's death, this town.
Only farmers and bandidos.
And I don't see a hoe.
You a bandido, America?
Uh, no. Uh, actually
I'm looking for a Senor Beck.
Senor Beck?
Right.
Ok?
You Beck?
I know who you are.
- Good. That'll make things easier.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
We cool?
- You're all the same.
Prepared.
This ain't America.
You want a drink?
Yeah, all right.
- Sit down.
Uh, is somebody using this chair?
So I guess you want to see it, right?
- Yeah.
You want to see it, don't you?
- Yeah. I'm afraid I'm gonna have to.
Hey.
You know what? Come with me.
Sorry. Sorry.
This is what they call the Mexican.
Wow. Yeah. That's pretty.
- You're shitting me? Yes, it's pretty.
Can I?
- Uh-huh.
It was made for a wealthy landowner,
a nobleman, by a poor
Mexican gunsmith.
He fashioned this gun as a gift
to go along with the hopes
that the nobleman's son
would take his only daughter's
hand in marriage.
The townspeople waited 3 months
to catch
the first glimpse of the pistol.
Then the day had come. No one had ever
laid eyes on a more beautiful gun.
It was everything they thought
it would be. Some even thought
it was too beautiful to look at.
It was considered to be an honor
and good luck
to be the first hand that
fires a newly fashioned gun.
Especially one as beautiful as this,
made for the hand of a nobleman.
The townsman was in a trance
at the gun's flawless craftsmanship.
It backfired,
killing him instantly.
Legend has it that
it's been cursed ever since.
But it hasn't harmed me
any though, you know.
I just, I love to look at it.
Let me show you something.
Look at that. There's a bullet
in there. Handmade.
Hand-fucking-made.
You don't even want to know
what this gun is worth.
We could sell that gun, man.
It's a
great fucking gun.
And I'm not just talking
shit either.
You don't have to be a... Fuck.
I've been pissin' on myself. Fuck.
Anyway, the old man
is nothing to be afraid of.
As a matter of fact, uh, just last
week I told him to fuck off.
Yeah, you did.
- That's what I said too!
I said, "Fuck off, Margolese,
you old prune shit-ass!" If you...
Come on, fella. Get up. Huh?
Man, you're soaked in your own urine.
Don't make me carry you.
Hey! Ah, this is my life.
All right.
Yeah, baby. I got the touch.
-Oh! Buddy, you whacked your noggin!
Hey.
Oh, f...
Oh.
Hey, man. Hey.
Oh, shit!
Stop that! Stop! Christ!
I found the gun.
- All right. It's in your possession?
As we speak.
But, like I said, there's, uh...
There's a little problem.
- What, what? You lost the kid?
Go to another bar, you'll find him.
- The kid's dead, Ted.
Ted, are you hearing me?
Yeah. I-I heard you. How?
Bad luck, act of God, the fuck if I
know. There's all these maniacs
shooting goddamn guns up into the sky.
It's Independence Day or something.
The kid got tagged by one on its way
down. Right in the fuckin' head.
I mean... He's dead!
The kid's dead. The little fucker's
in my car right now, dead.
- Jerry, that's not a little problem.
That's a big problem.
- I know.
Jerry, that is Margolese's grandson.
- What!
What?
- Geez, you really fucked it this time.
What did I have to do with it? First
he's pissin' himself, than he's dead.
Don't even move, ok? I'll call the
office. We'll get me on a plane.
I'll get down and help you shit out.
- You've gotta get word to the old man.
I didn't know who he was.
- Okay. Just sit tight, Jerry.
Hello?
Ted? Hello?
Wait! Wait!
Oh, no!
Excuse me, Bernie.
There is an issue.
It's that fuckin' Welbach.
You need to know straight out, I don't
stand for any motherfuckin' shit.
Mm-hmm.
- Mm-mm.
No shit at all. Understand,
this is what you're gonna do.
You're gonna stop crying.
And you're gonna walk out of here
with me. Can you feel me, Sam?
Good.
Shh.
Now, Sam, as I was saying...
No!
No, please! Please don't hurt me!
Help me! Help me!
Please. Please.
Where's your car? Where's your car?
- There!
Are you hurt?
- No. Yes.
I don't know. Truck, truck, truck!
Um, um... Sir?
Can you, can you stop the car? Please.
Why?
I'm gonna be sick. Just open up...
I'm not good in cars.
She told me, "Don't go. I don't want
you on that highway alone."
I said, "It'll be fine, Mom. It'll be
ok." But it's not, is it? I'm dead.
Well, you're not dead. You would have
been dead if I hadn't saved your life.
Would you rather it was you
back there? I didn't think so.
Are you gonna kill me?
Depends on too many variables
to answer right now.
Are you gonna rape me?
That's not likely, no.
- Well, geez, what do you want?
I suspect the same thing
as that guy back there.
The pistol.
The pistol that Jerry's havin' a hard
time coming back from Mexico.
Jerry?
I work for Bernie Nayman, who works
for Margolese. You heard of them?
Yeah, I've heard of them.
- You know your husband works for them.
No.
- Well, he does.
I know the selfish, no-good liar
works for them. He isn't my husband.
Well, whatever he is to you,
Jerry is in the shit books.
When you're deep in the shit, you get
a little skittish about your future.
Clouds your judgement.
There's a lot of people
interested in that gun.
So what we got here is,
"He who controls the girl, controls
the pistol" sort of a situation.
I am a hostage? You blew that guy
to pieces for a fucking gun?
This is so Jerry. All right, look.
- Sit down. Sit down.
Look. Jerry and I broke up,
so if he's doing...
I don't know what he's doing 'cause
it's got nothing to do with me. Zero.
You seem like a very nice girl.
- Thank you.
But it's a fact: In these
life-threatening situations...
human beings... lie.
So you are gonna kill me.
All right, look.
If everything turns out fine and Jerry
comes through without this all
getting funky, I don't think that'll
happen. He brings me the pistol,
I give you to him. I'm just here
to regulate funkiness. Ok?
Go on.
Great.
Hyah, hyah. Hyah! Hyah!
Come on, buddy. Come on. Ok?
Just you and me. Yeah.
Go!
Go. Oh! You're such an ass.
What are you...
No, no, no. I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
I didn't mean... Fuck!
Fuck!
Hey!
Buenas noches.
Um, I need a lift
to the next town in your truck.
I need a ride...
in your automobile to the next town.
I can't pay you.
I have no money. No dinero.
- De Niro?
Si. None.
- Robert De Niro?
Robert De Niro.
Yeah. Uh, I need a lift...
in your "el truck-o,"
to the next "town-o."
Uh, "village-o." Uh, uh, pueblo.
- Ay, pueblo.
Yeah, si!
- Al otro pueblo. Ok.
Yes?
- Senor De Niro.
Self-winding, man.
You never have to wind it.
It's very fine. Yeah. Shake like...
Perpetual calendar. It's good.
Is this even gonna run?
Hey, buddy. Is that your ball?
Shit. Hey. Hey, man.
You got a rabid dog back here.
Go. Go! Go. Out.
You gotta do something about this dog.
I have a collect call
for Samantha from Jerry Welbach.
There's no one there, sir.
- Second. She's there. Sam, pick up.
Sam? Samsonite?
Baby, please don't do this.
I'm sorry, sir. Please try again.
- No! A second. She's there...
What are you doing?
- Gonna make a phone call.
To whom?
- To Jerry. You're gonna tell him
that Leroy is with you, then hang up.
- Leroy?
Yeah. Leroy, that's right.
Then you're gonna hang up. Simple.
That's it?
- It's enough. Believe me.
Do I have to make you? 'Cause I will.
- No. I'll call.
Good.
Dial it.
- Ok. What's the number?
You have the number.
I don't know where he is. He's in
Mexico. You should have the number.
What are you tellin' me? You don't
have a number, motel, hotel, nothing?
What's the matter, don't you listen?
We broke up.
No longer together.
Why would I have the number?
I'm sensing you have trust issues.
You got one minute.
I'm a professional.
I do this for a living.
Goody for you.
You're wasting your time.
I think I believe you.
What's in Vegas?
Uh, well, I'm gonna be a waitress,
then make a career as a croupier.
They make a 100.000 dollars a year,
but you have to have the hands, such.
I got them from my Grandma Vega, which
is a good thing, 'cause Granny Barzel,
she had hands like a circus midget.
- How come you can't live with Jerry?
Do you know Jerry?
He has trouble expressing feelings.
He had a really fucked-up childhood.
His mom is nuts. One of those people
who thinks the iron is always on.
Don't you love him?
- I think that's the problem.
We love each other too much.
But he's just... He's so selfish.
It's like we've been living his life.
He'd tell you a different story,
but I give and he just keeps taking.
Our counselor totally agrees
with me, by the way.
I don't put much stock in those weirdo
counselor types. All they do is sit
around in bare feet and smoke joints.
- Maybe true, fact is, Jerry's a taker
and I'm a giver. It's obvious.
- You know, a lot of people
are under the impression that
you get to choose who you love.
I'm sorry, are you...
Are you taking his side? You're a man.
Of course. You're taking his side.
- You love him.
You said so yourself.
It's all that matters.
You're a very sensitive person
for a coldblooded killer.
Thank you, Sam.
Shit.
Get. Get out. Out.
Look, you gotta get out.
Get out!
Go!
Hola, shithead! Where's my stuff?
Where's my stuff? Get back!
Where's my stuff? Pistol. Pistolero.
- Pistola.
Get back! Stay calm!
Get back, get back! Don't move.
What the fuck? Give me those.
Back! Back, back.
Get in the car. Get in!
Ok. Is that my... Is that my jacket?
Put it in the car!
What is wrong with you people?
Get back.
You don't have to be in here.
- Well, I go by track record.
I don't hear any tinkle, tinkle.
- Stage fright. Look around,
there's not even a window.
So what's with this "we've been
livin' his life forever" thing?
Figure of speech. Jerry's been working
for Margolese for 5 years less a day.
It just feels lifelong.
Sounds like jail terms.
- It is.
Arnold Margolese is in jail
because Jerry put him there.
Jerry ratted out Arnold Margolese?
- No.
Jerry was coming across Ventura.
You know, over there by Laurel Canyon.
He wasn't paying attention,
ran a red light,
smashed into Margolese's Cadillac.
When the cops came,
Margolese got busted because
he had a person in the trunk.
That's how Margolese got sent to jail?
- Mm-hmm.
Live person or dead person?
- Live person.
Huh. What's the big deal, then?
- Probably wasn't gonna stay that way.
He was taped up in a trunk
for a reason, wasn't he?
God, I would think this was
right up your alley, Swifty.
He saw something.
- Well, whatever it was this guy saw
or was going to say to the cops, he
got the chance. And since it was
technically Jerry's fault, Margolese
had him work off the jail time.
You see, my whole relationship
has been hijacked
because he doesn't pay attention
when he drives.
I, I can't go
with you in here.
We didn't think we were getting
a dead man with the car.
I got no use for a dead gringo.
Take a left.
Go on.
If you're going to kill me,
at least you owe me the right to know...
who it is that's going
to send me to God. Tell me!
Look, I'm not gonna kill ya.
But I am gonna have to shoot you.
But why, sir? Why?
- Why? Why? Because you stole from me,
you know about the pistol, you steal
again. And I can't have you coming
back like a fly in the ointment.
- No! You'll never see me again.
You're gettin' shot, that's it. It'll
take you time to get to the next town,
especially if you're limping.
- Limping? Can't you just tie me up
some more?
I mean, fuck! You shoot me? Tie me!
Yeah. I don't have a rope.
- So you shoot me?
It's the American way.
Where do you want it?
Ok.
- No, not the leg! There's arteries.
I could bleed to death in seconds.
- The foot, then.
Look, that's fair where I come from.
Ok? It'll hurt, but it'll heal.
What if you take off a fucking toe!
Wait, wait, wait.
Not the left.
- Sorry. On the count of 3.
1...
Look, I'm agreeing with you.
But there's a few ways to look at it.
Sex is, no matter what anybody says,
an important part of relationship.
The fact that Jerry
is a considerate lover says a lot.
You lost me.
- Well, he's a considerate lover.
You just gotta find a way to get him
to expand this quality to other areas
of your relationship. I mean,
even if it only comes out in sex,
it's there just the same.
- That's a good point.
If a person's a considerate lover,
he can't be all selfish, right?
Unless of course he's...
he's, uh, being a considerate...
- What was that?
What?
- That. That moment you had.
What moment?
Leroy, you just checked out that guy
and had a moment. That was a moment.
I don't know if it was a moment.
Are you gay?
As in "happy"?
- As in homosexual.
What does my sexual orientation have
to do with we've been talking about?
Nothing. Nothing.
Except something that you said back
there really bugged me, and this
would kind of help it make sense.
- Yeah? What's that?
I asked if you were gonna rape me,
and you said, "Not likely."
You said it so matter-of-fact, like
I was repulsive and it was ludicrous
to think that I was actually at risk
of you wanting to have sex with me.
First of all, it's a crime of anger,
not attraction. And second of all,
you're not repulsive.
You're very beautiful.
Thank you.
- You want me to rape ya?
Are you gay?
You're gay. You're gay.
I knew it! Oh, I so knew it.
I just knew it. What a relief.
- You want, a medal? Saying
you identified a homosexual?
- No.
Are you full throttle?
Full throttle?
Yeah, I guess I am.
Oh. I'm not, I mean...
I'm not trying to be a smart-ass
or anything like that. I just,
I just think that this is great.
Wow. This is, this is... major, ok?
I know the kind of people
in your business. Ok?
Yeah?
- And to me, it seems that,
well, being gay isn't really...
conducive to the environment.
- Oh. Like I should be
an interior decorator.
That's insulting.
I am very good at what I do.
- Do you have a boyfriend?
No, I don't.
Unfortunately,
I seem to be unable to keep...
relationships together.
Seems like everybody's having trouble
keeping relationships together.
It's ringing, senor.
Thank you for that.
- No, no, no. No necesario.
Really?
That's so kind. You have no idea
what I've... Thank you. Gracias, man.
If this is my guy in need,
I'm on my way. Find your way to the
Hotel de la Plaza. Wait for me there.
- Ok, ok. Forget aeropuerto.
Uh, Hotel de la Plaza.
Hola.
- Is This your dog?
Sort of. Came along for the ride.
- He does have a personality,
and that certainly counts.
- He's a good guy.
Is this your car?
- It's a rental. I'm an American.
No shit? Really?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Well, I am Mexican.
Cool.
Do you have a passport?
Jerry "Wellbatch," Los Angeles, U.S.A.
- Welbach.
Well-batch.
Can I ask you a question, Jerry?
How long have you been here in Mexico?
A few days. Pleasure.
- I see.
Pleasure, huh?
- Yeah.
I see. Can you tell me,
uh, what happened here?
That's not accurate, I'm afraid.
The gunsmith did craft this pistol
for a prospective husband, and he was
a nobleman's son,
true. But the motif was darker,
my friend.
It's cursed, this gun.
The key to this tale
involves the gunsmith's assistant,
a poor, but honorable
young man in blinding love...
with the gunsmith's daughter.
For months at a time,
the assistant took to the mines,
gathering the precious metal...
that would yield the most
beautiful gun that ever existed,
only to discover that what he hoped
would be a wedding gift for him,
was for another.
The gunsmith insisted his
daughter marry the
nobleman's son,
forbidding their love.
So, angered in his bitter pain,
the assistant cursed the gun,
vowing the creation
would never prevail.
But the gunsmith was racing against
time. He had promised a pistol
of unparalleled craftsmanship,
the nobleman's dowry
hanging in the balance.
He worked day and night to
correct the pistol's problems.
This gun never worked properly.
Some say its very creation
ended the gunsmith's life.
Well, my friend, you're free to go,
but without the gun.
This gun doesn't belong to you or
to your boss. Now it belongs to me.
Yeah, Vegas. It can be tough that way.
- Expensive?
Yeah, emotionally. Let's just say that
I had a serious relationship problem.
Oh. You fit right in here.
What do you do now, Frank?
Now, I am... a postman.
Get out of here. Rigid.
- Swear to God. No, come on.
The postal service is busy, too.
- Is that the key to it?
And that's the key. You have no idea
how many small, unmarked
brown paper packages I deliver.
What, porno?
- Yeah, daily.
Like what?
- Videos, blow-up dolls, dildos,
pocket pussies.
- Don't leave nothing out.
Oh, yeah? Hmm.
But, you know, even with all that
dirty excitement at my fingertips,
I still have to take off once a year.
So I just walk out the front door and
I know I'm going to Vegas, but I don't
know how. All I've got is my wallet
and an attitude.
I don't know, it keeps me sane.
After all,
guns don't kill people.
Postal workers do.
All set, Mr. Shurker. In front there,
a shuttle will take you to your car.
What kind of car is it exactly?
- It's a Chrysler, sir, brand-new.
You wouldn't happen to have
something a little more...
Raoul!
Yeah, man!
- Yeah. Never fear, Teddy's here.
How are you?
Come on, Jerry. The Mexican thief, the
dirty cop? I mean, the word is out.
Big-ticket item. A lot of fucking
people are interested in that gun.
No fucking way. Is that what they
think? That I'm selling them out?
I don't know. Maybe they think you're
scared and might do the wrong thing.
You know, I don't know. I'm just
doing my goddamn portion here.
Yeah, and what is that?
- To find out what's going on, assess
the damage, try to calm you down,
help find the pistol, get us home.
I tell you, I get on that plane,
pistol or not, that'll be the last
fucking flight I ever take.
- Come, Jerry.
Come, Jerry? You know it.
- I know what I'm supposed to know.
Just doing your fucking part. You
hear yourself? You sound like fucking
Schultz from Hogan's Heroes.
I know nothing!
I'm not crazy about Nayman
running things any more than you are.
But I'm telling you, to do is keep
your nose clean, look straight ahead
and do what you're told. That's why
I'm 17 payments away from Boca Raton.
'Cause I do my fuckin' portions.
I don't care how you look at it. The
first step is to get the pistol back.
I never took a payoff in my life.
- I know where your loyalties lie.
But the kid's dead. The pistol's gone.
I mean, you can see how it looks,
right? Come on, Jerry.
You're my guy.
Not the safest dance.
I'm not going anywhere.
We are in the city
where I'm going to be living.
Go.
What's wrong? Huh?
You know when you're in a bad
relationship and you separate?
All of a sudden, everywhere
you look there's love and possibility.
I'm worried about Jerry.
Don't worry. I'm gonna call Nayman in
the morning. I'm gonna check in out.
You want me to stay?
I want you to go.
You sure?
I really want you to go.
I couldn't sleep all night.
Yeah.
No, he said he followed the cop to
the pawn shop. He's taking me
over there after breakfast.
We're booked on the 7:00,
if all goes well.
No, now wait...
No, you wait a minute, Nayman. Now
what do you gotta go and say that?
Well, now or later?
How could I misinterpret?
You didn't send the wrong guy.
I'm handling things.
But I never signed up for that.
Listen, I promise you, when I tell
him it will make a difference. Bye.
Hey, sweets. I keep calling and, uh,
I haven't heard a word from you.
I'm starting to wonder.
I know you're angry with me, but, uh,
you know,
"Ain't no sunshine when she's gone."
Ok?
I think she actually went to Vegas.
- I keep telling you, Jerry,
these women are problems, you know.
You should try to be like me.
I answer to myself. No hassles,
nobody ridin' my ass like a
goddamn horse in a saddle. Free.
- You keep yourself closed off so you
have no shot at meeting the right.
- Any can be the right woman
if the numbers work and you're
willing. No way. Not me.
You settle. You open yourself up.
You become vulnerable.
What's this sudden insight
into my relationship?
Okay, look, Jerry. She is in Vegas.
What?
- Hey, shit falls down, you know?
"Shit falls down."
- Margolese called Nayman pissed off
that you were fucking this up, told
him to keep an eye on Sam. In case...
In case I get any funny ideas.
And you're just telling me this now?
Don't break my balls. Concentrate!
- On what?
That gun is worth a lot. People know
you have it. Sam could be in danger.
No shit. Who did they put on her?
- Say you know of him. It's that
fucking psycho Leroy from Minnesota.
- Leroy!
Nayman had to do it. It was an order.
Margolese would know if he didn't.
Wait. They're just trying to scare me.
Well, that would sure do it for me.
We've all heard the kidney story.
Nayman wants us on that 7:00 flight to
Vegas, with pistol, no ifs, ands buts.
They'll meet us at airport, and then
Leroy will take the pistol to him.
Yeah.
I had to borrow. Do you mind?
Sleep well?
Yeah. And you?
Who's Winston?
Somebody I don't like very much.
- You can have that removed, you know?
Yeah, maybe I will someday.
You wanna get some breakfast?
At first,
I thought this guy is all right.
And then I'm thinking he's more than
all right, he's terrific.
But there's no way he's gonna
feel the same way about me.
Then I find out he does.
Then I'm thinking what happens when
he finds out what I do?
And who I am?
And what I've done?
So, who am I kidding, right?
Let's get serious.
What are you gonna do about it?
- I didn't have to do anything.
It happened absent of my will
to consciously make it happen.
Oh, really?
- I was a little drunk last night.
I took my gun and I put it up in the
towels in the bathroom, you know.
And he found it.
And he said: "The past doesn't matter.
It's the future that counts."
- Leroy.
See, life can change.
People can change.
I haven't cried in 12 years.
What are you lookin' at?
Don't look at me like that.
You're makin' it worse.
What are you, Barbara Walters?
It's just beautiful.
- Let's talk about something else.
What do you wanna talk about?
- Anything. Anything else.
Anything. Whatever.
What was it over, the last time you
cried? Let's talk about that.
Oh, yeah, that'll bring
the sun right out.
I heard it was this guy Leroy's mom.
- Ok, that's what we call "bullshit."
If I told one guy at the next
convention that you kept your mother
cut up in the freezer for 5 years,
you'd have a reputation too.
Fact or not, it makes no difference.
- Ted, you can't be so naive, man.
The guy's a star. What are you worried
about then if you think
he's all blowhard and bullshit?
- I met Leroy once, in Minnesota.
I shook his hand of 2 seconds.
He seemed like a nice enough guy.
Whether he lives up to this legend of
a psychotic is beside the point.
If he sit naked in a garage soaking in
gas lighting matches, I don't care.
What concerns me is he was hired
in the first place. Are you with me?
Geez, Jerry, you really met him?
- Oh, my God!
Hey, old Ted is not gonna let anything
happen, ok, Jerry? I'm here.
Thanks, Ted. I feel perfectly safe.
Hola.
- I no fuck around. Comprende?
Gun. Gun. Loaded.
Bang, bang. You, dead.
Do you have a speech impediment?
- Give me the fuckin' gun. The pistol.
The pistol?
You know what I'm talkin' about. Go!
- The pistol?
Okay, all right. What's your name?
- Joe.
Just do like the man says. We'll be
out of here before you know it.
The pistol, please.
- Ok.
Excuse me.
I got it.
Come on. Go.
Got it.
- Just have a seat right here, amigo.
Geez! Jerry, have you lost your mind?
- What you're talking about on phone?
Jerry, will you put the gun away?
- Was it to off me?
To off me?
- I would never...
Go ahead, deny it. Go ahead.
- Ok, Ok. Jerry, that's what he said.
So you were lying I would walk away?
- No, Jerry, that's what he said.
Then you're lying now about him
telling to off me. Which is it?
No. He told me to do it, Jerry.
- But?
But...
- But you're just doing your portion.
Isn't that how it works, Ted? 17
portions left for Boca Raton. Right?
I wouldn't do that portion.
Come on, I swear!
First they tell you to bring me in.
Second they tell you to take me out.
Why are you being told 2 contradicting
things? You don't ask a question?
I, I just, I, I don't know.
You don't think that's a little weird?
- Yeah, it's, it's weird.
Right! Because something's going on.
What is it?
Exactly. You don't know, 'cause you're
just doing your fucking part.
Well, I'm not going down
because you don't know!
See my predicament?
You're my guy, Ted.
You're my guy, Jerry.
Hold on. What happened here?
- Someone swan dive, off the balcony.
Come on.
Go.
No. Please, no.
No. No.
Coming.
Hello, sir. Sorry to intrude.
Are all parties
in your room accounted for?
- Yeah. Just me and my wife. Honey!
No, that's ok, sir. Thank you.
- What happened?
Sorry to have disturbed you.
- Is everything all right?
Leroy.
Pack your shit.
Shh, shh.
Psst.
You're a stupid motherfucker,
you know that? You're well dressed,
I'll give you that, but stupid.
Wear Kevlar? Huh?
Yeah.
Leroy.
Please don't do this. Please.
Oh, you think I should listen to her?
Huh? What do you think?
Huh?
Wanna know what I think?
Kevlar is for pussies.
This is for Frank.
My bag will make the flight, right?
- They'll run it down there.
I just need to see your passport.
- Yeah.
I'm afraid there's been a mistake.
- What? No!
No!
- Mr. Shurker probably has yours.
I told you in the beginning, if Jerry
comes through and nothing gets funky,
no problems. Well, shit got funky.
- Why isn't he here? Why? Why?
Give me a second? I'm trying to get
the fucking story here, all right?
Just take it easy and stop acting like
a kidnapped chick on a carton of milk.
Hmm. Yeah. You're right.
This is an offer for the gun.
Yeah. I can see how this looks.
I've just been trying to get some,
you know, better numbers together.
- You have no intention of giving the
gun to Margolese, do you, Bernie?
- Look, Bobby.
I know that you're loyal. And that's
good. Nobody's debating that.
Let me ask you.
In your skulking around, going through
private things in other offices,
did you manage to discover that he's
shutting us down? That's right.
You, me, everybody.
- I don't, I don't understand.
You didn't get the memo, the
severance package, the bonus? No?
No. Nothing.
- Yeah, me neither.
Difference between you and me is I
know when I'm being fucked, you don't,
'cause you're standing
on the wrong fucking line.
Let me help you get on the right side
of the line and do for you what
he should've done, Bobby.
He's changed in prison. I'm telling
you, something's changed him.
He's not the same guy.
- They're still holding.
What do you want me to tell 'em?
Can I count on your cooperation?
- Yeah, yeah, Bobby. I'm here. Yeah.
Yeah, that's his hotel.
Yeah, all right. Sure.
What?
- Plan B is now in effect.
I hope you don't get airsick.
Get in the car.
Hola, hola, senor.
- Hola, Senor Welbach.
Has the U.S. Consulate called back?
- No, sir, not yet.
This is a muy important call.
I've lost my passport, ok?
I'll be sitting here. Not gonna move.
- Senor Welbach,
you see that man over there?
Yeah.
- That's Mr. Williamson.
So?
- He's been waiting for that same call.
Really? What, the whole morning?
- Since March, senor.
Oh, come on.
Hotel De la Plaza. Yes, as a matter
of fact he's right here.
Senor, it's for you.
Oh. Oh. Hey. Yes, hello?
- You bastard.
"Hello?" Like, my life is great.
Everything is fine.
Sam?
- I thought you could be dead.
I've been worried sick, and you say,
"Hello"! Confirming room service?
Sam?
- I'm done with Mr. Jerry Welbach.
Mr. Hi. No, no.
- Ask about the gun.
Leroy? Did he fucking touch you?
- Do you have any idea
what I have been through, hmm?
- Multiply it by a 1,000 times and you
know vague conception of where I'm at.
- Isn't that typical, Jerry?
It's all a competition!
Tit for tat, tat for tit!
Stop yelling, damned! How are you?
Are you ok? Are you all right?
Where are you?
- Toluca Airport, Jerry.
And things are shitty, really shitty!
If he bring the pistol, everything ok!
- He doesn't care about that.
Only cares about himself.
- Why are you airing personal matters
with complete strangers?
- I don't think that you very classify
someone who you just perpetrated
a killing
with a complete fucking stranger!
And let me tell you something.
I can't find my Kotex cards...
- Sam, what did you say?
Jerry, just settle down.
- What'd you do to her?
Jerry, just settle down. Ok?
- Yeah.
We had a slight situation, but as a
professional I know what I'm doing.
So why don't we all just
chill out a minute here?
What happened? Did you get lost?
- Yeah, 5 fucking years ago.
What did you, I can't hear you.
- No, nothing. Nothing.
Nothing. I hope you have something.
- Yeah, well you just, you don't...
Just make sure you return her
with all 10 toes. You hear me?
Understand. Just come down here, pick
us up. We'll square things away.
You got a very special woman here.
But we all know how you can get!
So, let's not have any of that.
This is a time for selflessness.
What? Wha...
You all right?
Stupid gun.
Out!
I have to ask you a question.
And it's an important one, so I want
you to think about the answer
before you give it to me, ok?
- Ok.
When 2 people love each other,
but they just can't get it together,
when do you get to that point
where enough is enough?
That, oh, well, that's...
You know. You know it's over when...
Ok, I have, like,
these psychosomatic
insomniatic manifestations of...
Well, here's the thing about me.
I'm a product of my emotions versus
being a product of my environment,
like him, which he is, exactly,
just that environmental...
I, I need sunshine to grow.
That's who I am.
And with the projection of...
I have goals.
That's your answer?
- Yeah.
That's not right. I mean, there's a
right answer here, but that's not it.
Look. In my business,
you're surrounded by loneliness
and finality.
Now, I don't care what your take is
on an afterlife. When people die,
it's scary. And they go alone.
Now, the people that I send off...
that have experienced love,
they're a little less scared.
I mean, they're still scared,
but there's a calmness to 'em.
I think that comes from the knowledge
that somebody somewhere loved them
Now, I see that from time to time,
and I am awed by it.
I don't think I'd be telling you
any of this if it wasn't for Frank.
Anyway, it's, it's a loaded question.
Look, when two people love each other,
totally, truthfully,
all the way love each other,
the answer to that question is simple,
especially in your case.
When do you get to that point
where enough is enough? Never.
Never.
I just hope Jerry's not stupid.
What is he driving?
It's a funky rental.
I know we're all a little grouchy
right now. We'll get something to eat,
you'll get the pistol and then
we'll all go our separate ways.
Really separate ways.
- Now, don't start, Sam.
Shut up. I'll start because I have...
- Do not tell me to shut up.
We had an agreement, remember?
- Why don't we all shut up?
I will crash this car right now.
- Jerry!
I will. One more word out of you.
Another word, Sam. One more word.
I swear to fucking God.
- Naugahyde.
Ok!
- All right, Jerry!
You gonna shut up?
- Yes, yes, yes!
Jerry, I will, I will!
Stop the car, Jerry!
Stop the car.
Stop, stop, stop!
Oh, my God!
Jerry, I want you to know, you're the
craziest fucker I ever met.
You know what? Go! Go to Vegas.
I've had it!
Son of a bitch!
I had a flat down in Florida once,
out in the middle of nowhere.
So I go to the trunk,
there's no spare.
Four hours in the baking sun
waiting for a truck to come by.
Ow!
- Now I always check.
Let me give it a rip.
More muscles, you know what I mean?
Wouldn't kill the bastards to oil
these every once in a while, you know.
Fucking car rentals.
- Yeah.
Walk away, baby. Walk away.
- What did you do?
He was gonna kill us, Sam.
- Look at his head!
Stop! Listen! I met Leroy in 1997 in
Minnesota. And that's not him!
No, no, Jerry. Jerry, you made a
terrible mistake. He was my friend!
You made a terrible mistake!
- Baby, Leroy is black.
Leroy's black. Ok?
- No.
Yes! He's black.
African-American. A person of color.
The guy he killed in Vegas,
that's the real Leroy. That's
Margolese's Leroy. So, this guy...
Oh, I'm such an ass. Such an ass.
Of course. "Give the gun to Leroy.
He'll get it down to Margolese."
I'm being set up!
Nayman hires this prick
to take out Leroy,
get the gun and pin it all
on Jackoff Jerry.
Isn't that right, Mr. Winston Baldry?
Right! Well, I met Leroy, Winston,
there's no way you could have known
that. Your mistake. You fucked up.
I can't believe it.
Every fucking time.
Every fucking time. Not this time.
This time I win.
This time I win!
I fucking win!
Oh, my God.
I'm lucky I didn't
lose you three days ago.
I wanna go home.
Did you call about your passport?
Did you call the consulate?
Do you have enough money?
Yeah, I'm all right.
I wanna ask you a question.
It's a good one, so think about it.
If two people love each other,
but they just can't seem
to get it together,
when do you get to that point
of enough is enough?
Never.
They'll call. I've left 60 messages.
I said it was an emergency.
Why would Nayman ask you if you like
sex and travel? I mean,
what is it even supposed to mean?
That you fool around or something?
I tell you this whole, long debacle,
and this you have a problem with?
Yeah, because, when you ask someone
who is involved in a relationship
of the heart,
if they like sex and travel,
that's m-m-mean-spirited.
It's stupid.
I'll tell you this. We're not running
anymore. So done with the running.
Just packing and running... Sooner or
later, that phone is gonna ring.
We are going to get your passport and
you put that gun in Margolese's hand
where it belongs. Nayman is fucking
Margolese. That has got nothing to do
with us. By the grace of God or I
don't know what, you have managed to
Forrest Gump your way through this.
And just, if we run now,
we're gonna be running
the rest of our lives.
We want our life back.
Yes, baby, we do.
No, that can't be right. Could you
just check again? Ow! Baby, don't.
Margolese. "M" as in Mary.
Baby, can you turn that down?
You don't even speak Spanish.
Real emotion transcends language.
You don't have to understand
the words to hear their pain.
- No, that's impossible.
That's... Do you know when?
Ay-yi-yi. No, all right. All right.
Margolese is out. He got out this
morning. He's out. What is going on?
He's not supposed to be out Thursday.
- It is Thursday, hon.
What is it?
- Shh. Come on.
Just stay away from the window.
Shit. Shit.
Here, give it to me.
Good one.
What is it, boy?
Hey!
Hey, man, get out of there.
Come on. You're freaking me out.
Ow.
Where you taking me?
It's not your fault you know nothing
about this gun. You're American.
This gun does not belong to you.
Mr. Margolese.
I don't understand.
What's it gonna take, Jerry?
- What?
The gun. What's it gonna take for you
to give it to me and not to another?
Man!
- How much?
I don't know what it takes. I'm new in
the "fuck you" business. You tell me.
Mr. Margolese. What does it take?
- I didn't fuck you, Jerry.
I had Nayman send you down here,
but I didn't know
he was looking for a buyer. When I
found out he was looking for a buyer,
I didn't know who on my team was still
on it, or even if there was a team.
Who the fuck are these guys?
- They work for this man, Tropillo.
And who the fuck is Tropi...
You know what? Not even important.
One good reason why I shouldn't fight
to my death to not give you the gun.
If it comes to that, someone here's
gonna leave this room missing an ear.
Or not being able to fuck anymore.
One reason, now,
that you let me know
what you think I'm made of.
Are you a fatalist, Jerry?
Uh, I never really thought about it.
- Por favor.
Gracias.
When you do think about it, about that
afternoon, you smashed into my life,
into my car, ever think there's
anything to that?
I honestly never thought about it.
Because of that afternoon, I'm doomed
to remember a simple backwards inmate
with a paper clipping.
When you're in jail, a small box,
you learn a lot about
the fella you're in a cage with.
I grew to love that boy,
like he was my own son.
But he was his.
One day the boy came to me with a
paper clipping. "This is my destiny.
This is my birthright."
It was a story about the pistol.
How they found it in the mines stashed
away. When I asked why
it meant so much to him,
the story he told
changed my life.
The night before the nobleman's
arrival, the assistant could
not sleep, his heart in aching pain.
The day was upon him when the gunsmith
would present his gift to the nobleman
and his son.
The nobleman's son was a notoriously
vicious soldier, worldly and wicked.
For him, his father demanded
something more beautiful,
more perfect than he'd ever
laid eyes on before. But nothing,
no words or description
could have given justice to it
or have prepared him
for that gun's flawless grace.
When the nobleman's son
saw his intended bride-to-be,
it was love at first sight.
The nobleman's son took
the mighty weapon into his hands.
A perfect fit.
It did not work. The nobleman
took it as a bad omen.
The curse had rendered it
useless in unworthy hands.
The gunsmith urged him to try it one
last time, and so he did.
The nobleman was insulted
by the ineptness, angry with
the poor gunsmith. They argued.
When the nobleman's son realized that
her heart belonged to the poor,
simple assistant, a man far less than
he, he was furious in anger.
He could not have that.
The assistant, realizing that
even if the gun should work,
she would certainly die next,
begged his love
to withdraw and accept their fate.
Some say you could actually
hear her heart break.
She fearlessly surrendered
her bitter spirit unto purgatory.
The pistol contains
her damned soul.
Day after day I would listen to that
story. And always he would tell me,
"When I get out, I will find that
pistol and I will return it to
my father, whose father's father
had crafted the gun."
18 months later,
he took it in the belly for me.
He died.
I vowed to search, acquire the pistol
and return it to his father.
My grandson Beck, headstrong boy.
Sure, he was mixed up.
He didn't understand the honor
behind what I was doing.
That's when it became clear to me
I had to send you down here.
Because you were the instrument
in the situation, Jerry.
His son is dead.
My grandson is dead.
All of it brought together by that
afternoon at our intersection.
Well, that...
that's a pretty good fucking reason.
You are a soldier of God.
She will be safe there, right there,
and she can fly with the angels.
No devils can catch her here,
right here,
and now she will be able
to fly with the angels.
We square?
- I'll owe you.
Jerry, honey?
- I bet this is the queen of the idiot.
Am I right? This must be Sam.
This is Bernie Nayman.
Where's that stupid fucking Jerry?
With Leroy?
Don't you mean Winston?
I hope not, 'cause he's dead.
- Then you're in a lot of trouble.
Especially if Jerry sold that gun.
Jerry hid it.
- A step in the right direction.
Are you there, Sam?
- Yeah, I'm here.
Yeah, me too.
Nayman! Where is she?
What have you done with her?
Jerry, get me out!
- Don't shoot. She's in the trunk!
I swear to God, if you've hurt her...
- It is hot in there.
Let her out!
- Give me the pistol, I'll let her out.
All right. All right, Nayman,
where are the keys?
I might have lost them.
- You're shit, because she's the only
one who knows where the pistol is.
- Oh.
Sam, no!
- Put that down. You'll damage it.
You shut the fuck up!
- Sam, do not, I repeat,
do not pull that trigger. No, no, no.
- I will, I will pull this trigger.
You toast that gun,
he's dead right after.
Sweets.
Put the gun down. Ok?
Put it down.
It's not worth it.
Ok?
He's right, it's not worth it.
Don't you know when enough is enough?
Baby.
Do you like sex and travel?
As a matter of fact, I do.
- Wrong answer.
Sweetheart?
We just witnessed a miracle.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Are you all right, hon?
- Am I ok? Yeah, I'm ok.
You ok? Yeah?
May I?
- It would be our honor.
Yeah.
Seal it.
Do you love me, Jerry?
- I adore you, sweetheart.
Then tell me it again.
- Baby, I've already told you 3 times.
Just one more time, please.
Please. Please.
The pistol was crafted for a noble man
by a poor Mexican gunsmith.
Nobleman.
- Hmm?
It's nobleman, not noble man. 2 words.
- That's what I...
What difference does it make?
Why do you have to correct me?
English is your mother tongue.
- I'm calling a time-out!